<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with Patrick Fitzgerald</title>
    <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com"/>
    <description>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Patrick Fitzgerald</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-06-24 09:30:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>pat.fitzgerald@AcademyMortgage.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Get the answers to the most popular questions for you and to get the necessary tools to make a proper decision on a Home Loan using the Texas Veterans Land Board Program.</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Do When an Appraisal Comes Up Short</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-to-do-when-an-appraisal-comes-up-short.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-07 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+to+Do+When+an+Appraisal+Comes+Up+Short.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What happens when an appraisal comes up short of what a home is sold for? If the buyer has a VA loan, here’s what it looks like. 

Let’s say a home is sold for $250,000 to a buyer with VA financing. The mortgage company will send the appointed VA appraiser along with the contract for the property. The appraiser then goes to the property, measures it, looks at its condition, and formulates an opinion on its value. Then, the appraiser will go back and do some research to see what other, similar homes have sold for recently. 

This is why it’s so important for your Realtor to complete a CMA, or comparative market analysis. This will give you a great idea of what the home will appraise for before the appraiser even gets there. Both your Realtor and the appraiser use the same sold database to know what homes in the neighborhood have sold for recently. 

“I’ve had a short appraisal three times in the last 30 days.”

If the appraiser cannot find the value that’s on the contract, he declares Tidewater. This is a VA term that states the appraiser can’t find the value of the home that’s on the contract and gives the mortgage company 48 hours to find additional comparable properties to support the contract value.

Many times, this causes a great big problem. I’ve had this happen three times in the last 30 days, unfortunately. There are a few different ways with which to proceed in this, but it rarely happens. Typically, the seller will have to come down on the sale price to get the appraisal to come in. The VA buyer always has an out too and can cancel the contract if the appraisal comes up short.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime about any and everything VA loans, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+to+Do+When+an+Appraisal+Comes+Up+Short.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+to+Do+When+an+Appraisal+Comes+Up+Short.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>An appraisal that comes up short can completely derail a real estate transaction. Here’s how you can avoid it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>An appraisal that comes up short can completely derail a real estate transaction. Here’s how you can avoid it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>USDA Loan Changes Can Now Be Used for Manufactured Homes</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/usda-loan-changes-can-now-be-used-for-manufactured-homes.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-05 12:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-The+VA+Loan+Guy-+USDA+Loan+Changes+Can+Now+Be+Used+for+Manufactured+Homes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There have been some recent changes to the USDA loan in regards to manufactured homes.

Effective immediately in Texas, you can now use a USDA loan on pre-owned manufactured homes. What’s so cool about this? Well, the USDA loan is a zero down conventional loan program, meaning buyers don’t have to make a down payment.

This doesn’t mean all mortgage companies will do this, however. Each company has slightly different rules, so make sure you verify with yours.

“Each company has slightly different rules, so make sure you verify with yours.”

To qualify for the loan in Texas, you must have a credit score of at least 620, the home must be a double wide, and it must be permanently attached to the ground or retrofitted (the foundation must meet HUD guidelines). The home must have been manufactured after January 1, 2006, and it has to be sitting where it was originally installed. A move doesn’t include the transport from the dealer or factory to where it was installed; it means moving it from one address to another.

If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-The+VA+Loan+Guy-+USDA+Loan+Changes+Can+Now+Be+Used+for+Manufactured+Homes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-The+VA+Loan+Guy-+USDA+Loan+Changes+Can+Now+Be+Used+for+Manufactured+Homes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can now pay zero down for a pre-owned manufactured home. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can now pay zero down for a pre-owned manufactured home. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-Approval vs. Pre-Qualification</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-07 16:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Pre-Approval+vs.+Pre-Qualification.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to talk about the difference between being pre-qualified and being pre-approved. I get this question a lot, so I figured I’d answer it for you.

A pre-qualification means that a lender has pulled your credit, examined your documents, and submitted an automated online approval with Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac. 

A pre-approval contains all of the above, plus we submit the file to an underwriter. The underwriter looks at everything, asks for clarification, and makes a decision on whether you can afford a home or not. Once you’re pre-approved, you know exactly what you can afford.

“A pre-approval might take a few days longer, but it can save you a lot of trouble.”

If you’re a buyer in the market and out there making offers, a pre-approval shows sellers and their Realtors that your approval is firm and that you actually can afford the home. It’s a really important thing, especially in today’s market where multiple offers are common. 

A pre-approval might take a few days longer, but it can save you a lot of trouble. If you have any questions for me or need more information, don’t forget that it doesn’t cost a penny to talk. I’d love to hear from you. Just give me a call or send me an email today.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Pre-Approval+vs.+Pre-Qualification.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Pre-Approval+vs.+Pre-Qualification.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re deciding between getting pre-qualified or getting pre-approved, the choice is clear. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re deciding between getting pre-qualified or getting pre-approved, the choice is clear. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 More FAQs about the VA Home Loan</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/5-more-faqs-about-the-va-home-loan.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-21 12:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+5+More+FAQs+about+the+VA+Home+Loan.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Continuing from last time, here are the last five questions featured in our series about the 10 most frequently asked questions we receive about VA loans:

6. “Can I use my VA loan to buy raw land?” I get this question nearly every single day, and the answer is no. The VA loan does not finance the purchase of raw land all by itself. Here in Texas, we have a wonderful program called the Texas Veterans Land Board, which does finance raw land for veterans. If you’re from out of state, you’ll have to look into whether your own state has such a program.

7. “How long do I have to live in the house as my primary residence?” The VA program doesn’t really set a rule on that, but my advice to you is to stay at least 12 months in the home and fully establish your residence as your primary residence, meaning that you live, operate, and receive your mail there.

8. “Can I only use my VA loan once?” A veteran can use their VA eligibility to buy a home over and over and over, as long as the previous house has been sold or paid off. Some individuals may even be eligible to buy two houses at once.

“A good point of advice is to always check with the lender you’re working with, as some lenders have additional rules they impose on VA loans.”

9. “Can I pay my own property taxes and insurance?” No—the VA always requires that your property taxes and insurance be a part of your payment. If you’re disabled and pay no property taxes, then just your homeowners insurance would be a part of your escrow.

10. “Can I get another VA loan after filing bankruptcy?” The VA is very forgiving in that matter, so the answer is yes. You will have some eligibility left, and the rules are very specific: If you had a chapter 7 complete liquidation bankruptcy, you have to wait two years from the date of the discharge of the bankruptcy. If you had a chapter 13, you need only wait 12 months before being able to qualify for another home loan.

Following these questions, a good point of advice is to always check with the lender you’re working with, as some lenders have additional rules they impose on VA loans.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I’m available seven days a week, and it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+5+More+FAQs+about+the+VA+Home+Loan.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+5+More+FAQs+about+the+VA+Home+Loan.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In today’s second part of our series in which we address the top 10 most frequently asked questions, I’ll address questions six through 10.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In today’s second part of our series in which we address the top 10 most frequently asked questions, I’ll address questions six through 10.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Answering Your Top 10 Questions About VA Loans: Part 1</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/answering-your-top-10-questions-about-va-loans-part-1.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-07 16:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Answering+Your+Top+10+Questions+About+VA+Loans-+Part+1.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to launch the first half of a two-part series covering the top 10 questions I hear about VA loans. We’re going to share five of these common queries today and finish with the remaining five in our next message.

1. What kind of credit score do you need to qualify for a VA loan? Believe it or not, the VA does not set a specific threshold for credit scores. Instead, they allow affiliated lenders to set a parameter they believe to be appropriate. So if you’re curious about applying for a loan, yourself, connect with a local lender to determine whether you’ll qualify. Typically, though, the minimum limit will range between 580 and 640.

2. What kind of income counts toward qualification? Disability payments, child support, retirement income, pension, and many other sources can be applied to your application. So long as your income is steady and verifiable, it should qualify.

“If you have an experienced professional to guide you, it shouldn’t be too difficult to secure a VA loan.”

3. Is it difficult to obtain a VA loan? Actually, not really. Your debt-to-income ratio will be the most important factor, but if you have an experienced professional to guide you, it shouldn’t be too difficult to secure lending.

4. Can I have a co-borrower on a VA loan? Only spouses or another person with military benefits can act as co-borrowers on a VA loan.

5. What kind of property can a VA loan be used on? Single-family homes, duplexes, triplexes, or fourplexes can all be purchased using the VA loan. You can also buy a manufactured property so long as it sits on a permanent foundation.

This covers the first five of our most common VA questions. Be on the lookout for our next installment, at which point we’ll cover five more.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Answering+Your+Top+10+Questions+About+VA+Loans-+Part+1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Answering+Your+Top+10+Questions+About+VA+Loans-+Part+1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We get a lot of questions about VA loans, and we’re going to answer some of them today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We get a lot of questions about VA loans, and we’re going to answer some of them today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Escrow Holdbacks</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/escrow-holdbacks.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-24 14:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Escrow+Holdbacks.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When there are required repairs or renovations that show up on an appraisal, they can be paid for through what is called an escrow holdback.

As an example, I’m currently helping an elderly couple who don’t have the ability to make any repairs—but they do have the money needed to do so. In situations like this, we hold money back from the seller at closing to pay for any fixes that are needed. 

Escrow holdbacks are used for things such as roofing or flooring work; we won’t use it for room additions, foundations, kitchen upgrades, and other renovations that are unnecessary for the home. They should be done for minor, one- to two-day fixes.

“We won’t use escrow holdbacks for room additions, foundations, kitchen upgrades, and other renovations that are unnecessary for the home.”

Let’s say there’s $5,000 of work that needs to be done. The mortgage company will require 150% of the repair costs to be held at the title company. So in this case, the title company would hold back $7,500. Once the repairs are complete, the lender will send the appraiser to verify the work has been done. After this, the money is released to the vendor who did the work, and the remaining money is returned to the seller.

Keep in mind that not all mortgage lenders will conduct escrow holdbacks, so be sure the lender you choose is willing to.

If you have any questions about this process or would like some more information, feel free to give me a call at 210-215-4400. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Escrow+Holdbacks.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Escrow+Holdbacks.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Escrow holdbacks can pay for any last-minute fixes in your home. Here’s how.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Escrow holdbacks can pay for any last-minute fixes in your home. Here’s how.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Conforming Loan Limit Increases</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/conforming-loan-limit-increases.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-18 14:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Conforming+Loan+Limit+Increases.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’ll be talking about the recent increase to conforming loan limits and what it means for you.

The conforming limit is the maximum loan amount the government allows someone to borrow when using a conventional or VA loan. Essentially, it’s been increased because home prices have risen.

For 2018, the conforming limit has been $453,100—on January 2, this limit will increase to $484,350. For someone using a VA loan, this means they can borrow up to $484,350 with no down payment. A conventional loan of this same amount can be borrowed as well, but a 5% down payment is required.

“The conforming limit is the maximum loan amount the government allows someone to borrow.”

Of course, you can always borrow more than this limit when using a conventional loan, but then it becomes a jumbo loan—a different topic entirely.

Conforming limits on FHA loans will increase as well. Here in Texas, the limits (depending on the county) will be anywhere between $294,000 to $386,000. You’ll need to talk with your lender to figure out what the limit is for the county you’d like to buy a home in.

If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to contact us. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Conforming+Loan+Limit+Increases.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Conforming+Loan+Limit+Increases.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how conforming loan limit increases affect you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how conforming loan limit increases affect you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>1 Critical Step Unmarried Homebuyers Must Take</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/1-critical-step-unmarried-homebuyers-must-take.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-03 16:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+1+Critical+Step+Unmarried+Homebuyers+Must+Take.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Right now, I’m working on two separate files for unmarried couples planning on buying a home together. And with that being the case, I thought now was the perfect time to share my insight on this scenario. Is it really a good idea for an unmarried couple to purchase a home together?

Actually, the answer to this isn’t black and white. It is possible for the situation to go smoothly, but I still recommend that anyone considering this arrangement starts the process by speaking with an attorney and having a simple agreement written up.

This agreement doesn’t have to be elaborate, but it does need to cover both parties in the event that things go awry. Unmarried couples considering a joint home purchase should think critically about what will happen if they split up after closing, or if (God forbid) one of them passes away?

Couples without the legal protection marriage provides must think critically about these and other tough questions before making the move into homeownership.

An attorney will be able to guide you through such questions as you work together to draft the agreement I mentioned earlier.

“Meeting with a lawyer, drawing up an agreement, and having each of your signatures notarized could save you a lot of time, money, and hassle later on.”

To illustrate the importance of such an agreement, take the case of an unmarried older couple I worked with several months ago. Unfortunately, one of them passed away. And as difficult a thing as loss is to handle by itself, the scenario was made even more so by the fact that the decedent didn’t have a will. This meant his widow, who thought she owned the house completely, suddenly found herself in a partnership with her late partner’s children.

Having some form of document detailing each party’s intentions is essential in protecting against scenarios like these. And death isn’t the only circumstance that could pose problems for unmarried couples who purchase a home. As I touched on already, issues may also arise if the relationship comes to an end after closing. What if, for instance, the person moving out wants to be removed from the mortgage?

There are three ways this can happen: if the house is sold, the house is paid off, or the house is refinanced. If the person who decided to stay in the home does choose to refinance, however, they may struggle to qualify for a loan because they no longer have access to their partner’s income.

The bottom line is this: You don’t need to be married to buy a home with your partner, but (as is always the case) both parties involved in the purchase should be in agreement as to how they should proceed if something goes wrong. Meeting with a lawyer, drawing up an agreement, and having each of your signatures notarized could save you a lot of time, money, and hassle later on.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+1+Critical+Step+Unmarried+Homebuyers+Must+Take.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+1+Critical+Step+Unmarried+Homebuyers+Must+Take.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Purchasing a home is a major decision, so when unmarried couples choose to take on this responsibility together, they must be prepared for the difficulties that may arise.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Purchasing a home is a major decision, so when unmarried couples choose to take on this responsibility together, they must be prepared for the difficulties that may arise.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know Before Buying an Investment Property</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-you-need-to-know-before-buying-an-investment-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-30 13:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+You+Need+to+Know+Before+Buying+an+Investment+Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The rules for purchasing a rental property are highly specific, so anyone considering doing so should be aware of a few key stipulations.

First, realize that you will need a 20% minimum down payment. That said, the higher your down payment on an investment property is, the better—as is the case for other home purchases, as well.

The interest rate on an investment property will always be at least 0.5% to 0.75% higher than it would be for the purchase of a primary residence, but submitting a higher down payment can help reduce this cost.

Additionally, your debt-to-income ratio must be below 50%, and you will need to have a sum equivalent to at least six months’ worth of mortgage payments for your primary residence reserved in your bank. In the case of a $1,500 payment, this means you’ll need at least $9,000 in savings, a money market account, an investment account, or some other form of liquid account.

“I highly encourage anyone able to meet the stipulations we’ve discussed today to pursue building wealth through real estate.”

Retirement accounts can also count toward this, but only 60% of the funds within such accounts will be considered—given that retirement accounts tend to hold a penalty associated with liquidation.

And if you have more than one investment property, you’ll need to multiply this reserve amount by however many properties you accrue.

Finally, don’t forget that you’ll need to budget for closing costs—that is, unless you can negotiate for the seller to pay them.

The rental market is very strong right now, so I highly encourage anyone able to meet the stipulations we’ve discussed today to pursue building wealth through real estate.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+You+Need+to+Know+Before+Buying+an+Investment+Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+You+Need+to+Know+Before+Buying+an+Investment+Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you know what it takes to buy an investment property? Let’s review the requirements you’ll need to meet before making such a purchase.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you know what it takes to buy an investment property? Let’s review the requirements you’ll need to meet before making such a purchase.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Freeze Your Own Credit?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/can-you-freeze-your-own-credit.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-12 11:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Freeze+Your+Own+Credit_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve ever had your credit pulled without your permission or you’re worried about identity theft happening to you, a new federal law was recently passed that allows you to freeze your credit if you want to.  

The best part? You can do it for free.

“A new federal law was recently passed that allows you to freeze your credit if you want to.”

All you have to do is contact all three major credit bureaus—Transunion, Equifax, and Experian—by phone, written mail, or online, and ask them to lock down your credit. If you make this request online or by phone, your credit will be frozen within one day. If you do it through written mail, your credit will be frozen within three days.

Then, if you want to unfreeze your credit at any time, all you have to do it contact them again and ask.  

As always, if you have any questions about this topic or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk, and I’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Freeze+Your+Own+Credit_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Can+You+Freeze+Your+Own+Credit_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A new federal law was recently passed that allows you to freeze your credit at any time for free.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A new federal law was recently passed that allows you to freeze your credit at any time for free.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Zero-Down Home Financing for the Rural Homebuyer</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/zero-down-home-financing-for-the-rural-homebuyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-06 10:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Zero-Down+Home+Financing+for+the+Rural+Homebuyer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to take a closer look at USDA home loans and the benefits they bring to homebuyers.

A USDA home loan is a loan guaranteed by the U.S. Department of Agriculture. It doesn’t work everywhere, however—the purpose the of the program is to help with financing homes in rural areas. You will not get approved for this loan inside a city with a population of more than 25,000.

As a type of conventional loan, the USDA loan uses a conventional appraisal. Similar to the VA loan, it doesn’t require a down payment at all. The borrower must have a 620 credit score (at least with my company), and there will be a small private mortgage insurance amount that you will be expected to pay.

“The USDA home loan program is a great product if used properly.”

For all USDA home loans, there is a maximum family income. This varies based on the location of the home, which is why you need to make sure to check with your loan officer. For example, in the San Antonio area, the maximum income for a family of four cannot exceed $82,700 in order to be eligible for the USDA loan. Of course, larger families have higher maximum incomes.

The USDA home loan program is a great product if used properly, and it has helped many families in less populous areas in the nation. To find out if a home you are looking at qualifies for a USDA loan, you can go here.

If you have any questions about it, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Zero-Down+Home+Financing+for+the+Rural+Homebuyer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Zero-Down+Home+Financing+for+the+Rural+Homebuyer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re unsure about what a USDA home loan is for or how it works, this overview should give you a clearer idea.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re unsure about what a USDA home loan is for or how it works, this overview should give you a clearer idea.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Credit Repair Companies Do to Fix Your Score</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-credit-repair-companies-do-to-fix-your-score.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-23 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+Credit+Repair+Companies+Do+to+Fix+Your+Score.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to talk about credit repair. What is it? And how can it help fix your credit score?

Before I get to that, however, I want to talk about the things that cause credit problems. Obviously, late payments and collections both contribute to a negative credit score. More recently, I have also seen broken apartment leases negatively impacting people’s credit scores.

There is the common misconception that when you pay off a past-due bill,  it is no longer on your credit report. This is wrong because even if you have a $0 balance, the damage is done and it is still reporting as either a derogatory or late payment on your credit report. In fact, it will remain on your report for seven years unless you or a credit repair company works on removing it.

Something else that you need to know is that 83% of all credit reports today have errors of some kind on them. These can be anything from the wrong dates being reported, the months that you have paid off not being present, or items that aren’t even yours appearing on your report. It’s important to be aware of these errors because your score can make or break your ability to obtain a mortgage. 

“Credit repair companies basically bombard the credit bureaus with letters questioning every negative thing on your credit report.”

So what actually does credit repair do to help you? Credit repair companies basically bombard credit bureaus with letters questioning every negative thing on your credit report. Is it effective? Absolutely, because, under federal law, the credit bureaus have just 30 days to respond back and clarify whether that item is really true or not.

If the creditors do not respond within 30 days, federal law requires that the negative item come off your credit score permanently. Since the credit repair companies question these things, the bureaus have no choice but to remove it from your report if they do not get a response in time.

You should know that there are lots of people in the credit repair business that take your money and then not do anything. You need to be very careful with who you hire to do this.

I can always refer you to several credit repair specialists I’ve worked with successfully who do a wonderful job. Or, you can ask around and get some references from people that have used them personally. You want to be sure that they are people who know what they are doing.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+Credit+Repair+Companies+Do+to+Fix+Your+Score.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+Credit+Repair+Companies+Do+to+Fix+Your+Score.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you know how credit repair companies work? Today I am explaining what they do to fix your score.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you know how credit repair companies work? Today I am explaining what they do to fix your score.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Knowing Your Deductible</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/the-importance-of-knowing-your-deductible.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-11 10:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+Importance+of+Knowing+Your+Deductible.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you know what your insurance deductible is?

In most cases, people tend to select a 1% rate in case of things like hail or fire damage. This means that if someone with a 1% annual rate has a $250,000 home, then their deductible would amount to $2,500.

But in some cases, people may take shortcuts and attempt to get a lower annual rate on their insurance premium by selecting a rate of 2% or 3%. This can land you in hot water, though. To explain why, I’d like to recount a scenario I encountered recently.

“The last thing you want to do is cut corners to save a few pennies up front, only to wind up paying for a major expense later on as a result.”

Just last week I had a client who was selling his $250,000 home. When the inspector came out to examine the home, he declared the roof to be a total loss as the result of hail damage. My client picked up the phone and called their insurance company, who sent out an adjuster that agreed with the inspector’s claim.

Because the client had selected a 2% rate rather than a 1% rate, he will be forced to pay $5,000 of the total $10,000 that’s needed to repair the roof. It just goes to show how quickly things can creep up on you.

The bottom line is that you’ve got to make sure you know what your insurance policy and exposure actually is. The last thing you want to do is cut corners to save a few pennies up front, only to wind up paying for a major expense later on as a result.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+Importance+of+Knowing+Your+Deductible.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+The+Importance+of+Knowing+Your+Deductible.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Knowing your deductible is incredibly important. So if you aren’t already informed as to what yours is, you need to find out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Knowing your deductible is incredibly important. So if you aren’t already informed as to what yours is, you need to find out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Home Warranties Are so Important</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-home-warranties-are-so-important.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-21 14:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Why+Home+Warranties+Are+so+Important.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When buying a home today, receiving a clean report from the home inspector does not mean you are out of the woods. Systems or appliances in your home could fail a week, a month, or even years down the line. And they may no longer be under warranty, meaning that you will be the one to pay if something goes wrong. That is, if you do not have a home warranty policy.

Having a home warranty policy can protect you from such expenses. You will be offered such a policy at closing, but it is still possible to obtain a home warranty even after this point.

These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense. Systems and appliances like stoves, dishwashers, garage door openers, air conditioning units, water heaters, and more are among the items these policies cover.

“These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense.”

So, given how catastrophic a cost replacing or repairing these items could be, it is clear why a home warranty is so critical. Think of it this way: Wouldn’t you rather pay a fixed cost for a home warranty policy each year rather than shelling out who knows how much for an unexpected disaster? There are some exceptions, but for the most part, the only cost you pay when ordering a repair through your home warranty policy is the charge for the service call.

In my last decade as a homeowner, I have had two air conditioning units, my dishwasher, my garbage disposal, and my garage door spring all fail. You never know when a system or appliance in your home may fail.

And if a standard policy isn’t sufficient for your needs, you may consider signing up for a premium or enhanced policy. These offer even more protection.

Between your real estate agent and title company, you will have access to a wealth of knowledge and resources in the process of selecting which home warranty policy is right for you.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Why+Home+Warranties+Are+so+Important.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Why+Home+Warranties+Are+so+Important.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are a number of reasons why having a home warranty policy is so critical for today’s homeowners. Today I would like to highlight just a few.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are a number of reasons why having a home warranty policy is so critical for today’s homeowners. Today I would like to highlight just a few.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Homeowner’s Insurance Policy Should You Choose?</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-homeowners-insurance-policy-should-you-choose.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-31 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+Homeowners+Insurance+Policy+Should+You+Choose_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I get a lot of questions about homeowners insurance from clients as well as Realtors. So, today I’d like to discuss a few important points about this subject.

Rates are going up sharply due to some pretty massive national losses from a lot of the insurance companies. Hurricane flooding in Houston and other natural disasters in California are creating massive claims for insurance companies, driving up the costs. But, you should know that if you are going to finance the home, homeowner’s insurance is mandatory.

Many times, insurance companies try to get your business by offering you a low rate. However, they increase the deductible over the usual 1% deductible.

Let’s say that you have a $250,000 house with a total roof loss due to hail and a new roof costs $10,000. To reach your deductible you will have to pay $2,500, which means you will get a check for $7,500 to pay for your roof.

If you elected to take a 2% or even a 3% deductible, you are going to get next to nothing for that roof. Since the roof still needs to be repaired, this can take a major toll on your checkbook. For this reason, you should be careful what deductible you select when you choose coverage.

“You should select a policy with a 1% deductible even if it has a higher rate because if something does happen a higher deductible could mean you spend more.”

There are many coverage options available today. You should select replacement coverage. This type of coverage means that if you have a fire and all of your furniture is destroyed, you will get brand-new furniture even though it may be old.

Foundation, sometimes called slab, coverage will protect you from cracking due to covered events. You also want water coverage for any seepage of water or broken pipes in the slab. Water can cause a tremendous amount of damage.

What controls the rates you get, though? Credit scores, the age of the home, the age of the roof, and location all influence your rate.

Many people also wonder about bundling their insurance and if they will get a deal. When you combine your auto insurance and homeowners insurance with the same company, you can get discounts on both. Always ask for the bundle deal.

If you want to know more about insurance, you can go to the Office of Public Insurance Council’s website. Here, they have information about homeowners insurance broken down into coverage, what it means, etc.

If you have any additional questions for me, please feel free to contact me by phone or email. I would be happy to assist in any way that I can.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+Homeowners+Insurance+Policy+Should+You+Choose_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+Homeowners+Insurance+Policy+Should+You+Choose_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What homeowner’s insurance policy should you choose? I am here to help you decide.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What homeowner’s insurance policy should you choose? I am here to help you decide.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Patrick Fitzgerald</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
