<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with Patrick Fitzgerald</title>
    <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com"/>
    <description>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Patrick Fitzgerald</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-06-06 09:50:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>pat.fitzgerald@AcademyMortgage.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/img/podcast.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Get the answers to the most popular questions for you and to get the necessary tools to make a proper decision on a Home Loan using the Texas Veterans Land Board Program.</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to Do When an Appraisal Comes Up Short</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-to-do-when-an-appraisal-comes-up-short.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-07 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+to+Do+When+an+Appraisal+Comes+Up+Short.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What happens when an appraisal comes up short of what a home is sold for? If the buyer has a VA loan, here’s what it looks like. 

Let’s say a home is sold for $250,000 to a buyer with VA financing. The mortgage company will send the appointed VA appraiser along with the contract for the property. The appraiser then goes to the property, measures it, looks at its condition, and formulates an opinion on its value. Then, the appraiser will go back and do some research to see what other, similar homes have sold for recently. 

This is why it’s so important for your Realtor to complete a CMA, or comparative market analysis. This will give you a great idea of what the home will appraise for before the appraiser even gets there. Both your Realtor and the appraiser use the same sold database to know what homes in the neighborhood have sold for recently. 

“I’ve had a short appraisal three times in the last 30 days.”

If the appraiser cannot find the value that’s on the contract, he declares Tidewater. This is a VA term that states the appraiser can’t find the value of the home that’s on the contract and gives the mortgage company 48 hours to find additional comparable properties to support the contract value.

Many times, this causes a great big problem. I’ve had this happen three times in the last 30 days, unfortunately. There are a few different ways with which to proceed in this, but it rarely happens. Typically, the seller will have to come down on the sale price to get the appraisal to come in. The VA buyer always has an out too and can cancel the contract if the appraisal comes up short.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime about any and everything VA loans, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+to+Do+When+an+Appraisal+Comes+Up+Short.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+What+to+Do+When+an+Appraisal+Comes+Up+Short.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>An appraisal that comes up short can completely derail a real estate transaction. Here’s how you can avoid it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>An appraisal that comes up short can completely derail a real estate transaction. Here’s how you can avoid it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>USDA Loan Changes Can Now Be Used for Manufactured Homes</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/usda-loan-changes-can-now-be-used-for-manufactured-homes.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-05 12:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-The+VA+Loan+Guy-+USDA+Loan+Changes+Can+Now+Be+Used+for+Manufactured+Homes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There have been some recent changes to the USDA loan in regards to manufactured homes.

Effective immediately in Texas, you can now use a USDA loan on pre-owned manufactured homes. What’s so cool about this? Well, the USDA loan is a zero down conventional loan program, meaning buyers don’t have to make a down payment.

This doesn’t mean all mortgage companies will do this, however. Each company has slightly different rules, so make sure you verify with yours.

“Each company has slightly different rules, so make sure you verify with yours.”

To qualify for the loan in Texas, you must have a credit score of at least 620, the home must be a double wide, and it must be permanently attached to the ground or retrofitted (the foundation must meet HUD guidelines). The home must have been manufactured after January 1, 2006, and it has to be sitting where it was originally installed. A move doesn’t include the transport from the dealer or factory to where it was installed; it means moving it from one address to another.

If you have any questions or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-The+VA+Loan+Guy-+USDA+Loan+Changes+Can+Now+Be+Used+for+Manufactured+Homes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-The+VA+Loan+Guy-+USDA+Loan+Changes+Can+Now+Be+Used+for+Manufactured+Homes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can now pay zero down for a pre-owned manufactured home. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can now pay zero down for a pre-owned manufactured home. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Pre-Approval vs. Pre-Qualification</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-07 16:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Pre-Approval+vs.+Pre-Qualification.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to talk about the difference between being pre-qualified and being pre-approved. I get this question a lot, so I figured I’d answer it for you.

A pre-qualification means that a lender has pulled your credit, examined your documents, and submitted an automated online approval with Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac. 

A pre-approval contains all of the above, plus we submit the file to an underwriter. The underwriter looks at everything, asks for clarification, and makes a decision on whether you can afford a home or not. Once you’re pre-approved, you know exactly what you can afford.

“A pre-approval might take a few days longer, but it can save you a lot of trouble.”

If you’re a buyer in the market and out there making offers, a pre-approval shows sellers and their Realtors that your approval is firm and that you actually can afford the home. It’s a really important thing, especially in today’s market where multiple offers are common. 

A pre-approval might take a few days longer, but it can save you a lot of trouble. If you have any questions for me or need more information, don’t forget that it doesn’t cost a penny to talk. I’d love to hear from you. Just give me a call or send me an email today.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Pre-Approval+vs.+Pre-Qualification.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Pre-Approval+vs.+Pre-Qualification.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re deciding between getting pre-qualified or getting pre-approved, the choice is clear. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re deciding between getting pre-qualified or getting pre-approved, the choice is clear. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 More FAQs about the VA Home Loan</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/5-more-faqs-about-the-va-home-loan.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-21 12:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+5+More+FAQs+about+the+VA+Home+Loan.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Continuing from last time, here are the last five questions featured in our series about the 10 most frequently asked questions we receive about VA loans:

6. “Can I use my VA loan to buy raw land?” I get this question nearly every single day, and the answer is no. The VA loan does not finance the purchase of raw land all by itself. Here in Texas, we have a wonderful program called the Texas Veterans Land Board, which does finance raw land for veterans. If you’re from out of state, you’ll have to look into whether your own state has such a program.

7. “How long do I have to live in the house as my primary residence?” The VA program doesn’t really set a rule on that, but my advice to you is to stay at least 12 months in the home and fully establish your residence as your primary residence, meaning that you live, operate, and receive your mail there.

8. “Can I only use my VA loan once?” A veteran can use their VA eligibility to buy a home over and over and over, as long as the previous house has been sold or paid off. Some individuals may even be eligible to buy two houses at once.

“A good point of advice is to always check with the lender you’re working with, as some lenders have additional rules they impose on VA loans.”

9. “Can I pay my own property taxes and insurance?” No—the VA always requires that your property taxes and insurance be a part of your payment. If you’re disabled and pay no property taxes, then just your homeowners insurance would be a part of your escrow.

10. “Can I get another VA loan after filing bankruptcy?” The VA is very forgiving in that matter, so the answer is yes. You will have some eligibility left, and the rules are very specific: If you had a chapter 7 complete liquidation bankruptcy, you have to wait two years from the date of the discharge of the bankruptcy. If you had a chapter 13, you need only wait 12 months before being able to qualify for another home loan.

Following these questions, a good point of advice is to always check with the lender you’re working with, as some lenders have additional rules they impose on VA loans.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I’m available seven days a week, and it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+5+More+FAQs+about+the+VA+Home+Loan.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+5+More+FAQs+about+the+VA+Home+Loan.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In today’s second part of our series in which we address the top 10 most frequently asked questions, I’ll address questions six through 10.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In today’s second part of our series in which we address the top 10 most frequently asked questions, I’ll address questions six through 10.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Answering Your Top 10 Questions About VA Loans: Part 1</title>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/answering-your-top-10-questions-about-va-loans-part-1.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Patrick Fitzgerald</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-07 16:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Answering+Your+Top+10+Questions+About+VA+Loans-+Part+1.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to launch the first half of a two-part series covering the top 10 questions I hear about VA loans. We’re going to share five of these common queries today and finish with the remaining five in our next message.

1. What kind of credit score do you need to qualify for a VA loan? Believe it or not, the VA does not set a specific threshold for credit scores. Instead, they allow affiliated lenders to set a parameter they believe to be appropriate. So if you’re curious about applying for a loan, yourself, connect with a local lender to determine whether you’ll qualify. Typically, though, the minimum limit will range between 580 and 640.

2. What kind of income counts toward qualification? Disability payments, child support, retirement income, pension, and many other sources can be applied to your application. So long as your income is steady and verifiable, it should qualify.

“If you have an experienced professional to guide you, it shouldn’t be too difficult to secure a VA loan.”

3. Is it difficult to obtain a VA loan? Actually, not really. Your debt-to-income ratio will be the most important factor, but if you have an experienced professional to guide you, it shouldn’t be too difficult to secure lending.

4. Can I have a co-borrower on a VA loan? Only spouses or another person with military benefits can act as co-borrowers on a VA loan.

5. What kind of property can a VA loan be used on? Single-family homes, duplexes, triplexes, or fourplexes can all be purchased using the VA loan. You can also buy a manufactured property so long as it sits on a permanent foundation.

This covers the first five of our most common VA questions. Be on the lookout for our next installment, at which point we’ll cover five more.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Answering+Your+Top+10+Questions+About+VA+Loans-+Part+1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://www.thevaloanguy.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Patrick+Fitzgerald/New+Videos/The+VA+Loan+Guy-+Answering+Your+Top+10+Questions+About+VA+Loans-+Part+1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We get a lot of questions about VA loans, and we’re going to answer some of them today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Patrick Fitzgerald</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We get a lot of questions about VA loans, and we’re going to answer some of them today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Texas Veteran Loans, VA Loans, The VA Loan Guy, Loans for Active Military, Mortgage Banking Firm, Mortgage Banking in Texas, VA Mortgages</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Patrick Fitzgerald</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Patrick Fitzgerald</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
